# KEERTHI GOPIREDD









http://www.linkedin.com/in/lakshmi-keerthi https://lakshmi-keerthi.github.io/my\_portfolio/ https://github.com/lakshmi-keerthi

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Data Scientist with 6 years of professional experience, including 4 years in the AI/ML field and 2 years as a student assistant. Pursued Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence at the University of North Texas, with a focus on Machine Learning. Actively seeking opportunities to implement my learnings in real-world business problems while continuously learning and evolving in the field.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of North Texas | Denton, Texas | Jan 2023 - Dec 2024 Master of Science, Artificial Intelligence | CGPA: 4.0

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University | Hyderabad, India | Jul 2014 - May 2018 Bachelor of Technology, Electronics and Telematics

## SKILLSET SPOTLIGHT

- **Python Programming**
- **MATLAB**
- Machine Learning Algorithms (Supervised and Unsupervised)
- **Neural Networks**
- Natural Language Processing
- **Computer Vision**

- Scikit-Learn
- NumPy, Pandas, OpenCV, NTLK
- Matplotlib, Seaborn
- TensorFlow, Keras and PyTorch
- **Descriptive Statistics**
- **Inferential Statistics**
- **Data Analytics**

- SQL, HiveQL
- Tableau
- Power BI
- Dataiku
- RapidMiner
- **MLOps**
- Microsoft Excel

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**



## wipro) Wipro Technologies:

#### Data Scientist

Aug 2021 to Dec 2022

- Client Huawei Ads Platform: Analysed and prioritized 150+ features post exploratory data analysis along with ensemble-based feature selection methods
- Implemented early stop and performed effective hyper-parameter tuning for an advertisement type and observed significant improvement on real-time data
- Fine-tuned predictive models, including Deep and Cross Network and FiBiNET, achieving an AUC score of 0.863 for predicting ad click-through probabilities
- Extracted data using HiveQL on regular basis from large datasets in HDFS to identifying patterns and insights to support data-driven decisions
- Played a major role in identifying automation scope and automation of capturing KPI from logs using Python scripts
- Client Citi Bank: Automation and streamlining data cleaning and pre-processing using customer and beneficiary databases using Dataiku Platform

## **a** Amazon:

# **Data Quality Specialist**

Aug 2018 to May 2021

- Worked under Amazon Robotics in Amazon Vision Operating Centre (AVOC) currently known as Go-Artificial Intelligence (Go-AI) handling 5+ AI/ML based projects
- Responsible for synchronizing the needs of machine learning models with the standard operating procedure used in the project to identify the ground truth
- Streamlined trouble ticket process to eradicate low confidence ML outputs which increased the probability of identifying the root cause by 30% and decreased manual effort by ~20%
- Solely worked for Canvas, a robot used to transport items in Fulfilment centres, focusing on visual inspection, image segmentation and feature extraction to build a novel model using neural networks
- Worked on pre-processing and interpretation of data for 5 visual inspection ML models which include damage detection, human detection, failure mode detection, compliance and safety detection.
- Automated mail triggers using SharePoint and weekly reports sent to fulfilment centers decreasing manual effort by ~70%

#### ACHIEVEMENTS AND ACCREDIDATIONS

- Merit Certificate with Excellent Grade in 'Advanced Certification Program in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning' organized by IIIT Hyderabad and Talent Sprint
- Completed 'Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certification' by ACES Academy at Amazon
- Awarded with 'Champion IDS Research Analyst' in Q2 2020 at Amazon
- Awarded with 'Champion Auditor Silver' in Q3 2020 at Amazon
- Accredited as the 'Most Valuable Player' in the audit team for the year 2020 at Amazon
- Awarded with 'Champion Auditor Gold' in Q1 2021 at Amazon
- Recognized as 'Outstanding Contributor' in February 2022 by the client (Huawei)

#### KEY MACHINE LEARNING PROJECTS

Participated and completed 8 hackathons as a part of 'Advanced Certification Program in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning' organized by IIIT Hyderabad and Talent Sprint. Main Hackathons include:

Literacy rate prediction | Colab using Python | Jan 2020

The goal of this Mini-Hackathon was to predict whether the literacy rate was high/medium/low in the different districts of India using multiple datasets and comparing the performance of multiple machine learning algorithms.

Speech classification | Colab using Python | Mar 2020

The objective of this Mini-Hackathon was to identify and classify simple vocal utterances such as 'yes' or 'no' using audio samples and tree-based machine learning algorithms

Developed multiple machine learning and deep learning models as a part of my Master's program on **Artificial Intelligence** at the **University of North Texas**. Key projects include:

- Leveraging Deep Learning Models for Bird Species Classification | Deep Learning | Fall 2023
  Focusing on Convolutional Neural Network (CNN), ResNet, DenseNet, and Vision Transformer (ViT) models involving training on feature-augmented image data to capture complex visual characteristics. This was implemented using Python programming language on the Google Colab
- Generating Synthetic Faces using Generative Adversarial Networks | Machine Learning | Spring 2023
  Developed a generative model using pre-trained models capable of producing realistic, high-quality synthetic faces indistinguishable from real faces. This was implemented using Python programming language on the Google Colab.
- Pneumonia Detection using Neural Network | Software Development for AI | Spring 2023

Trained and improved the ability of a Convolutional Neural Network to identify if a patient has pneumonia using X-ray images. Created a local website to display the prediction when a new X-ray image is uploaded. Training of the model was done using Python programming language and deployment of the model to a local webpage was done using Streamlit.

# CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Worked as a Digital Imaging Student Assistant (Feb 2023 Dec 2024) at the University of North Texas:
  - ➤ Captured metadata for 100+ historical letters
  - ➤ Digitized 20+ archival books and ledgers with perfection.
- Participated in MATLAB Arduino course and completed a mini project on CNC controller
- Completed Rapid Miner Machine Learning Professional and Master Certification
- Participated in 'Ethical Hacking' workshop conducted in Technocruise Hyderabad by Techkriti, IIT Kanpur